I just watched the war on Sun sneaking
three with Jamie wheel the infinite game
and in it he talks about how a lot it's
an hour long but that we are already in
the infinite game it already started
we're already kind of working towards
there and to hold these diabolical goal
these opposing views at the same time
but the founding fathers were horrific
human beings and they offered something
game a is both the best we've ever done
and horrible he is about his words
that's why his language but that we
can't tear down our current system and
create something from the burning
wreckage that's even if it feels like
that's what we want to do that's not a
great thing to do and I agree we have to
build the scaffolding that is anti
fragile within game a and it has to be
an active day B has to be a natural
attractor it has to deal with that we
are eco an ethnocentric some of the
times every human being nearly every
human being there are some that are that
are the outliers who are extremely
competitive and never want to cooperate
and those that are coming extremely
cooperative and never want to compete
but most of us are in between most the
best majority of us have competitive and
cooperative nature we just have to
choose which one to feed and our
competition piece is gonna show up
absolutely we're gonna get our egos hurt
because we don't get the likes and we
don't get the views and we don't get the
money we don't get the prestige owned
that keep coming back to the table
like yeah that didn't feel good okay
what is there for me to learn in that
when we truly get our individual power
or individual authenticity that nobody
else can be you and bring your ideas and
your experience to the table cuz they're
not you you arrived natural cooperation
because what's not easy for you is easy
for someone else and vice versa what
might trigger me in another person is
both here to teach me something and
exactly what they need to be to be the
match to my personality to
something else forward and you don't
ever have to sit with someone who
triggers you constantly to be able to
create the tools to allow our individual
selves the space and security the
feeling of safety that we need to be
able to grow and reach higher levels of
consciousness there becomes a natural
state in this ego to a national centric
to worldcentric that once you're beyond
a certain point you start to see the
beauty in all of the levels that
everyone is exactly where they're
supposed to be we're not all gonna get
to worldcentric
at one kumbaya moment some of us are
gonna get there and we're gonna create
the thing that helps people to cooperate
without needing to get there you can be
egoic and still create can be you can be
ethnocentric and still create game be if
there's something in it for you because
it's Omni win and an survival risk so
when you see that you living your genius
in your path even a little bit give
something to you that no money no
prestige no can can take away from you
it isn't of itself the incentive and you
start seeing that in other people they
start giving their genius and you start
seeing oh oh the Commons has our genius
so the more I put in the more you put in
we just have to we don't even have to
like flip game a to start incentivizing
cooperation we just have to create a
parallel game where cooperation thrives
where winning means being anti rival
risks and own that as individuals we're
gonna suck it in a lot of the time
because we're raised in game a and so
our ego is gonna come up we're gonna
feel gross good because someone else is
that our idea we didn't get recognized
for it we're gonna own that and
move forward we're gonna figure out okay
if what groups do I need so that I can
feel like I'm on my SEAL team not
there's one elite group at the top who
gets to be the SEAL team and everyone
gets kicked off every you know one Miles
Davis played jazz and if you can't play
at his level you're out everyone gonna
have a jazz band everyone can have a
seal team you don't have to be on mine
so there can be levels of capacity
levels of like right to be here you have
to be a code or be able to talk Tech to
be here you have to be you know a
Olympic athlete and be able to compete
it's not like we randomly assign a
hockey team and play the Olympics
they're still gonna be levels of genius
in those areas and you have to be there
to play on this team but everyone can
have a team everyone can be concluded it
can be everyone together we just have to
create the technology that makes that
possible where everybody's invited and I
do not have to sit with you when we
create that and we are creating that
with together tech we are getting there
it is happening out in the open for
everyone to see I'm doing it out in the
open for everyone to see and the more
people join that process not necessarily
together Tech but just the process of
you becoming more authentic the more you
follow that the more you see the other
people's authenticity them being
different than you is a gift not a
hindrance but you can't demand that
about their people just like you can't
demand to rule Omega you can't demand
other people see your diversity you can
only see your diversity and get there
and honor them in their current
capability which is maybe their eco an
ethnocentric and we all spend times in
that place we're all gonna lose our
and be triggered and we're gonna come
back to the table and if we don't come
like that's your choice to come back to
the table or not but the more of us keep
coming back and being like that didn't
work and keep coming back and talking
through it and having the hard
conversations
he doesn't think a conversation is that
powerful
Jamie wheel it's like that's not
circling great but it's not really doing
anything and yeah it is I'm having
conversations that are powerful amazing
and they are changing
they are the meditation of group but if
you're not there yet it's just about
getting you there which is having
conversations that aren't at the
circling level when we create the tools
to allow people to have real
face-to-face video conversations see
each other's humanity we do evolve
beyond ethnocentric because we see
ourselves on the other and we see how
they're people who are like us are
different just cuz they look like us
doesn't mean they're the same and just
cuz they look different doesn't mean
they're different and you can hold those
two different opposites you're both like
me and nothing like me and thank God for
that
because that is what is gonna get us to
game B is when we truly embrace our
individuality groups that see us and
accept us because that pays itself that
is Omni win that is a natural attractor
not kumbaya to everyone in this group
has to be the same bring you and find
your people and we're gonna create the
tools to do that
when we do that the chatty Cathy's and
needing ads don't take over the group
because it's not it's designed that
those people exist they can find their
people give their unique genius and
purpose and they're not disraeli in the
entire conversation because they're
circling there's conversations going
around everywhere everyone's able to tap
into what their geek is and find their
geeky this group and give that back to
the Commons an own that it's gonna be
hard when we're like but where do I make
money we're doing right no we don't need
to make money we need to solve resources
for everyone we just make sure
everyone's needs are met and it isn't
going to be flip a switch for playing
game be it's gonna be this road to
authenticity meeting other people who
are on their Road forming groups
creating projects the projects help
figure out how to live on how to get
more and more resources for less and
less money and time and so it's a
self-perpetuating system as we continue
along it it's going to prove itself
people will wake up to their genius and
there will be conflict and will hit
the fan all of it we can hold those two
opposing opposite
I'm here to hold those two opposing
opposites so a better world is on its
way and we are all gonna create it
together everyone is invited you're
invited to the whole you maybe can't sit
at my table in sit at my table I'm
pretty open because I can see the beauty
and diversity but you might not be able
to sit at my friends table
it's almost a ten minute video but this
is the one because it is a better world
is on its way please like and subscribe